Everything in Sahaja Yoga is very scientific,
霎哈嘉瑜伽裡的一切都是非常科學的
is all pre-planned I think, and is all significant.
都是預先計劃好的，而且都很重要
For example, today is Wednesday
例如，今天是星期三
and we have never had any Puja on a Wednesday
我們從來沒有在星期三辦過過崇拜
because I was born on Wednesday.
因為我是在星期三出生的
So I was thinking if the Puja starts before twelve o’clock
所以我在想如果崇拜能在十二點之前開始
we’ll be able to manage it
我們將能夠辦得很好
because I was born at twelve.
因為我是在十二點出生的
So every child has to sleep after twelve o’clock, you see,
因為每個孩子都必須在十二點後睡覺
and so I couldn’t, I had to sleep. So it’s so significant, you see.
所以我也必須入睡。意義是如此重要
It’s the first time we are having a Puja on Wednesday,
這是我們第一次在星期三舉行普濟崇拜
normally I don’t even travel on Wednesdays.
通常我甚至不會在星期三旅行
So, you can imagine that it’s such a breakthrough and I’m very happy
所以，你可以想像這是一個重大的突破，我非常高興
that you all are ready for a Puja
你們普濟都準備好了
and that we could break this rule also,
所以我們也可以打破這個規則
after such a long time,
經過這麼長的時間後
because it was impossible for me to keep awake after twelve, you see
因為在十二點之後使我非常難以保持清醒，你明白嗎
I was trying, trying, trying
我一直在試，努力，努力
and I knew that you all, also, were feeling very sleepy.
我知道你們大家也都感到非常困倦
So it’s so mutual and it’s so simple.Alright.
所以這麼相互且如此簡單。好吧
So today we have gathered, really, remarkably,
所以今天我們聚集在一起，真的，非常不簡單
in the really centre of the Nabhi of the universe,
在宇宙真正的臍輪中心 (希臘雅典)
and I don’t know how far
我不知道我能對這個偉大的國家
I can go with the description of this great country
——我們稱之為希臘
which we call as Greece.
——的描述能多長遠
Also, in the Puranas it is described as Manipura Dweep.
在《普拉那經》中，它被描述臍輪 (馬尼普爾 德威普)
The Manipur is the Nabhi Chakra – Manipur,
馬尼普爾是臍輪 – 馬尼普爾
and a “dweep” is a island.
而“德威普” 是一個島嶼
Island of the Manipura stays the Athena,
雅典娜女神駐在臍輪島
and there is a temple of Athena,
有一座雅典娜的神廟
all been described about Her temple, about Her
有關她的神廟、她的
jewelry, dress and everything.
珠寶、服裝和一切
So it’s already in the Puranas described, this Athena.
所以在《普拉那經》中已經描述了這位雅典娜女神
As I’ve told you before, ‘Athena’ means the Primordial Mother.
正如我之前告訴你的，“雅典娜”意味著太初之母
So now, one may say that,
現在，有人可能會說
“Why the Primordial Mother, Adi Shakti,
“為什麼太初之母
should be on the Nabhi Chakra of the universe?”
駐在宇宙的臍輪上？”
One may ask a question like that,
有人可能會這麼問
that, “Why She’s placed on the Nabhi Chakra?”
“為什麼祂被放置在臍輪上？”
Because in the – I don’t know in English –
因為在 – 我不知道英文怎麼說 –
before the Creation was created in the material form,
在創造物以物質形式被創造出來之前
where it was planned,
在那裡它被計劃
then there was something of the –
然後有一些關於 –
what we call is the Vishnuloka,
我們所稱的"毘濕奴界"
is the loka, or the area where Vishnu ruled,
或毘濕奴統治的地區
and in that Vishnuloka it was decided
在毘濕奴界中，決定了
that Adi Shakti should first come in the form as a cow,
太初之母應該首先以牛的形式出現
and then She should descend in the area called as Gokul,
然後她應該降臨到"哥庫"的地區
which is Vishuddhi Chakra,  first
即喉輪
and create vibrations there.
並在那裡創造靈量振動
Now in the material form the Gokul was
以物質形式來看，哥庫是
where Shri Krishna lived in His childhood.
克里希納童年時居住的地方
So in the material form, Athena itself lived –
所以在物質形態中，雅典娜本身生活著 –
in the material form, I’m not saying in the formation before –
因此，在物質形態中，雅典娜本身就生活在這個區域 –以物質形態，我不是說創造之前的形態
in this area, to create the vibrations.
——在這個區域，創造靈量振動
So it is not only She was a Goddess
因此，她不僅是一位女神
but She lived in this area
她生活在這個地區
to create the vibrations for the Nabhi,
為臍輪創造靈量振動
to create the universal
創造普世的
compassion and love and all Her qualities.
慈悲和愛以及她的所有特質
Now as you know, every aspect of the Goddess has different qualities
現在，如你所知，女神的每個面向都有不同的特質
and as you can see that Mahakali has the aspect of comforting,
而正如你所見，摩訶迦利女神具有寬慰人心的特質
and Mahasaraswati is counselling,
而摩訶薩維德麗女神擁有諮詢的特質
and the Mahalakshmi has got
而摩訶拉希什米女神具有
for the redemption, for the awakening.
救贖和覺醒的特質
But the Adi Shakti’s work
但太初之母的工作
is to unite everything, to integrate everything;
是將一切統一，整合一切；
and to integrate all those qualities,
整合所有女神的特質
the Adi Shakti Herself was…
太初之母本人
in material form, came on this earth, in this part,
以物質形態來到這個世界，在這個地區
and that’s why they knew about Athena.
這就是為什麼他們知道雅典娜
But as it is,
但事實是
I don’t know what are the stories they have–
我不知道他們有什麼故事–
they must be having some mythological stories about Athena
他們一定有一些關於雅典娜的神話故事
that She lived like this or whatever it was.
她是這樣生活的，或者不管那是什麼
And this is the…
這裡就是
where She created the Devaloka.
她創造天界的地方
Devaloka is the area where devas existed.
天界是神祇存在的地區
Like She created Indra –
就像她創造了因陀羅 –
you have heard the name of Indra – then Varuna;
你聽過因陀羅的名字 – 然後是瓦魯納；
all these devalokas She created in this area, not in India.
她在這個地區創造了所有這些天界，不是在印度
Devaloka was created on this side,
天界是在這一邊創造的
and ganas and all these people were created
而神靈和所有這些人都是在
on the side of Nepal and all those places, on the left-hand side.
尼泊爾和相連地方的左側創造的
Now unfortunately after Socrates, who came here
現在不幸的是，在蘇格拉底之後，他在這樣的情況下來到這裡
in such a condition when people were really,
當的人真的非常無知
absolutely ignorant, in the complete darkness of ignorance,
在完全的無知黑暗中
they could not understand Him,
他們無法理解他
they could not understand Socrates at all
他們根本無法理解蘇格拉底
and so like any other Primordial Master was treated
所以就像其他太初導師一樣
by the people who were surrounding Him,
被圍繞在他身邊的人們
He was also very much ill-treated and nobody listened to Him.
他也受到非常不公正的對待，沒有人聽他的
But of course, as you know, He was Primordial Master
當然，如你所知，他是太初導師之一
and His wisdom is well-known and He created out of Him
祂的智慧是眾所周知的，他創造了他的門徒
disciples, but none of them could go anywhere near His wisdom,
但他們中沒有一個人能接近他的智慧
and they started their own theories, own styles,
他們開始了自己的理論，自己的風格
and that’s how we find the accent from
這就是我們如何找到蘇格拉底的目標
philosophy that was Socrates’ aim,
從哲學的升進
gradually came into political and then into economic side.
逐漸進入政治領域，然後進入經濟領域
So the attention was moved from philosophy
所以今天的注意力從哲學轉移
to economics today,
到了經濟學
not towards the philosophy which was established by Socrates.
而不是蘇格拉底建立的哲學
We can say Socrates was the one Primordial Master,
我們可以說，蘇格拉底是繼亞伯拉罕和摩西之後
after Abraham and Moses, who really made it
真正對靈性有非常清晰認識的
very clear-cut understanding about spirituality.
一位太初導師
Of course Moses and Mohammad…
當然，摩西和穆罕默德
Abraham had different problems.
亞伯拉罕面對了不同的問題
Like Abraham had problems of talking to people
就像亞伯拉罕很難
who were  really very, very ignorant,
與那些非常非常無知的人交談一樣
and Moses had problem with people who were very indulgent people,
摩西與那些非常縱慾的人有問題
so He had to pass laws of Shariat.
所以他不得不頒布伊斯蘭教法
Moses passed the law of Shariat,
摩西頒布了伊斯蘭教法
and if you read Bible, in the –
如果你讀過聖經
I think – in the first verse only it is written about Shariat
我想，在《聖經》第三本書《耶利米書》（利未記？）的第一節經文中
in the Jeremiah (Leviticus?), third book of Bible,
只有關於伊斯蘭教法的內容
that Moses had to pass these laws, different, different laws
摩西必須頒布這些法律，不同的法律
to make the people follow religion precisely.
使人們嚴格遵循宗教
So He did not argue, He did not say
所以他沒有爭辯，他沒有說
why you should do it, didn’t give any explanation. “You do it!” Like that.
為什麼你應該這樣做，他沒有給出任何解釋。“你就這樣做！”他說。就這樣
Because He thought that these people are so ignorant
因為他認為這些人是如此無知
that you cannot leave it to their freedom
以至於你不能讓他們自由地
that you understand this or
理解這一點
that you see the point;
或明白要點；
He could not do that way.
他不能那樣做
So He just said, “Alright. These are the laws, these are the things
所以他只是說：“好吧。這是法律，你必須遵守
and you have to follow. If you don’t follow then you will be killed,
如果你不遵循，你就會被殺
your hands will be cut, this will happen, that will happen.”
你的手會被砍掉，這會發生，那會發生。”
Because the people were of that type.
因為那些人就是這種類型的
Now then you see how gradually,
現在你可以看到
at the time of Socrates people had evolved,
在蘇格拉底時代，人們是如何逐漸進化的
they were a much better people
他們比較進化
so He could talk to them about something
因此他可以與人們談論
of wisdom, of honesty, of righteousness, of peace.
智慧、誠實、公義、和平
Of so many things He talked,
他談了很多事情
and He could talk because people were worthy of that.
他之所以能夠談論，因為人們已經進化
Otherwise He could have said, “Alright.
否則他可以說：“好吧
You do this, you do that, you do that.”
你這樣做，你那樣做，你那樣做。”
But see the difference also in the circumstances how what has happened:
現在看看這些情況的不同之處：
in the first circumstances when Abraham had problems
在第一種情況下，當亞伯拉罕遇到問題時
then the people were absolutely good-for-nothing,
人們絕對一無是處
absolutely good for nothing, so He didn’t know what to do with them.
完全無知，所以祂不知道該怎麼處理他們
So only, you can see it, in the time of Abraham that His own lifestyle…
所以你可以看到，在亞伯拉罕的時代，祂自己的生活方式……
I mean, that was just a system when the family was building up
我的意思是，那是一個系統，當家庭
and the relationships were building up,
和人際關係建立時
and He tried to work it on that level.
而他試圖在那個層面上運作它
Then at the time of Moses people evolved much more.
然後在摩西時代，人們進化得更多
They evolved but still very ignorant.
他們進化了，但仍然非常無知
So they evolved to this point
當人們進化到了這個程度
that He did not have to talk the things that Abraham talked.
摩西不用再說亞伯拉罕談論過的事情
So He talked to them about getting out of Egypt,
祂跟人們談論如何離開埃及
taking their freedom, getting out from there
獲得自由，從那裡走出來
and going to a place of more tranquillity.
前往一個更寧靜的地方
But when they did that,
但當他們這麼做時
He found these people on the way –
他看到這些人在離開埃及的路上 –
when He went to get the Ten Commandments,
當他去取十誡
when He came back – what He finds…
回來時——他發現了……
So the people who were at the time of Moses,
在摩西時代的人們
when He had gone to get the Ten Commandments,
當他去取十誡時
started indulging into very, very immoral character,
開始沉迷於非常非常不道德的性格
extremely immoral character.
極其不道德的性格
They were very immoral and were doing such horrible things that
他們非常不道德，做著非常可怕的事情，以至於
that nobody can believe that anybody
沒有人能相信當初這些人
who tried to escape from the Egyptians
嘗試逃離埃及人的恐怖統治
were worse than the Egyptians themselves.
卻比埃及人還要糟糕
So He gave this Shariat to them, to change.
所以祂給了他們這個伊斯蘭教法，來改變他們
Now then came the time when people were…
現在，我的意思是
I mean, despite all that people were not so good,
儘管我們可以說在基督時代
we can say at the time of Christ,
人們並不那麼善良
but they were not so immoral;
但他們也沒有那麼不道德；
they also could not understand Christ.
他們也無法理解基督
So you see, despite all the human evolution,
所以你看，儘管人類不斷進化
the human awareness evolving,
人類意識不斷進化
the understanding about spirituality was very poor
但對靈性的理解卻非常貧乏
and you could not talk to them.
你無法與他們交談
Now you can also see the circumstances of things.
現在你也能看到事情的來龍去脈了
When the circumstances are such,
當情況如此時
like at the time of, say Moses,
比如在摩西的時代
that people are extremely immoral,
人們極其不道德
they are doing all kinds of bad things,
他們做各種壞事
they are not bothered about their own destruction,
他們對自己的毀滅毫不在意
the Incarnations had to move absolutely to the right
轉世神祇們必須完全向右脈移動
because they were so left-sided:
因為人們是如此偏向左脈：
So the Incarnations had to move absolutely to the right
所以轉世神祇必須完全向右脈移動
and say that, “If you do like this,
並說：“如果你這樣做
this We’ll have to do” the violence part.
我們就必須這樣做" 的暴力部分
So they took to violence.
所以人們轉向暴力行為
So the circumstances made the reactions of the people,
因此，情況使得人們的反應變得...
also the awareness of human beings.
也就是人類的意識
So many things worked it out.
有很多事情是這樣解決的
Say, for example, when Athena came on this earth,
比如說，當雅典娜女神來到這個世界時
her job was to create a integrated force
她的任務是創造一個整合的力量
which will have the whole chaitanya spread like an integrated force.
這將使整個靈量震動像一股整合的力量一樣擴散
So that when it will be all disintegrated later on it can integrate.
這樣當完全解體發生後，就可以重新整合
So the Greeks have a job, special job, is to integrate.
所以希臘人有一個任務，特別的工作，就是整合
You have to integrate people
你必須整合人們
which are left-sided and right-sided.
左脈和右脈的人們
And that’s what I asked him, “What happened to Hitler?”
我問他：“希特勒發生了什麼事？”
So they said that when they saw Hitler,
他們說當他們看到希特勒時
though Hitler respected them, they resisted Hitler.
雖然希特勒尊重他們，但他們仍然抵抗希特勒
You can see the significance, how he respected the Greeks
你可以看到這個意義，他是如何尊重希臘人的
and despite that they resisted him
儘管希臘人仍然抵抗他
because they were given this special capacity.
因為他們被賦予了這種特殊的力量
Something with Greeks, they went to…
和希臘人有關的，他們去了……
I mean, except Alexander, only the one
我的意思是，除了亞歷山大，他
who tried to invade India,
嘗試入侵印度
and because of the Greek nature he receded back.
而因為希臘人的本性，他返回了
You see it’s a Greek nature
你看這是一種希臘人的天性
that they can go so far and then not,
他們可以走很遠，然後停住不繼續往前
because they have an integrating force.
因為他們有一種整合的力量
The same thing as I was asking him about what happened with the Turks.
同樣的事也發生在土耳其
They had gone into Turkey but they receded back.
他們已經進入土耳其，但又退回去
So this power of receding back
所以這種退回的力量
is the integrating power,
就是整合的力量
by you integrate within yourself
由你在內心整合
both the qualities of the left and right and you balance it,
左右脈兩種特質，然後你平衡它
and you see now that’s alright.
你現在看到就是這樣了
If you have to be in the centre
如果你必須在中脈
we should go up to a point and come back.
我們應該向上一段距離然後回來
And this is a very basic quality of Greeks in every respect.
這方面是希臘人非常基本的特質
If you take their shipping,
如果你看看他們的航運
they were very aggressive in shipping to begin with,
他們在航運方面一開始就非常積極
extremely aggressive people,
極具攻擊性的人
and Greek ships were known for not maintaining at all.
而且希臘船隻以完全不維護而聞名
They were not very law-abiding
他們也不太遵守法律
so they were never used to maintain their ships, you see,
所以他們從來不維護他們的船隻，你看
and always under trouble – the Greeks –
而且總是惹麻煩——希臘人——
that in the shipping they were known to be, the Greeks have
在眾所周知的航運業中
ships which are all falling off and rattling.
希臘人的船隻都在脫落並且搖搖晃晃
So perhaps, perhaps,
所以也許，也許
they were aware that now the shipping is going to go down,
他們知道現在運輸業將會下滑
so no use maintaining these ships, you see.
所以不用維護這些船隻
Then when the shipping went down –
然後當航運滑落時 –
you see this is on economic level I’m saying, how they worked it out
你看，這是我所說的經濟層面，他們是如何解決問題
they sunk their ships
他們沉沒了自己的船
and got the money out of insurance.
然後從保險獲得了錢
That is a typical Greek style of behaviour
這是一種典型的希臘人做事風格
is that they know already. It’s a kind of a wisdom,
就是他們已經知道了。這是一種智慧
they know that how far to go.
他們知道該走多遠
Like, we can see now, Onassis also married this mad woman,
像我們現在看到的，奧納西斯娶了這個瘋女人
Kennedy’s wife, because  he must have realised
甘迺迪的妻子，因為他一定意識到
that Kennedy never gave her any security so he married her.
甘迺迪從未給她任何安全感，所以他娶了她
Alright. He married her up to a point,
所以。他在某種程度上娶了她
but most of his property went to his daughter,
但他把大部分財產都留給了他的女兒
not to Mrs. Kennedy.
而不是給甘迺迪夫人
This balance and this wisdom is a special Greek style of life;
這種平衡和智慧就是希臘一種特殊的生活方式；
that’s why you might say that they are not over-developed
這就是為什麼你可能會說他們並沒有過度發展
like Americans are.
像美國人那樣
But now Americans have realised that they are idiots,
但現在美國人已經意識到自己的愚蠢
but Greeks can never become idiots,
但希臘人永遠不會變得愚蠢
whatever you may try.
無論你怎麼看
They are very sharp and very intelligent
他們非常聰明且非常智慧
but they know how far to go with everything.
因為他們知道在一切上該走多遠
And what is the reason for this? The Athena.
這背後的原因是什麼？雅典娜女神
So Athena is the one, Adi Shakti,
所以雅典娜就是那位，太初之母
and She created Ganesha here.
她在這裡創造了象頭神
And the balance of the universe,
以及宇宙的平衡
or all the dharmas, is in the Nabhi Chakra,
或所有的道德正法，都在臍輪中
and so the people over here are very balanced.
所以這裡的人非常平衡
You can find them very…
你可以很容易地發現他們
in their language, in their styles, very deep.
在他們的語言中，在他們的風格中，非常深刻
One may say because they are traditional people,
有人可能會說因為他們是傳統的人
they have long traditions.
他們有著悠久的傳統
But Egypt had also long traditions.
但埃及也有著悠久的傳統
Of course Egyptians are, in a way,
當然，埃及人在某種程度上是
wiser than all other Islamic countries,
比所有其他伊斯蘭國家更智慧的
but not like Greeks, not like Greeks.
但不像希臘人，不像希臘人
We have Chinese also who are very wise,
我們也有中國人是非常具有智慧的
and they are known to be people of deep understanding,
他們被認同是深具理解力的人
but they are not like Indians.
但他們與印度人不同
So what is lacking in all these people is
所以在所有這些人中缺乏的是
the depth of awareness
意識的深度
because, though in China also Mother of Mercy came
因為，儘管在中國也有觀音的出現
and She really bestowed blessings upon them,
她確實賜予了中國人祝福
and China rose also, afterwards,
中國也隨之崛起
into her own glory
進入祂的榮耀
and became quite a good industrial,
並且變得相當好的一個工業國家
I mean developed country, we can say, very powerful;
我的意思是已發展的國家，我們可以說，非常強大；
but still, that kind of regimentation could not be borne
但仍然，他們無法忍受這種嚴酷的管制
because, after all, Mother Mercy was there.
因為，畢竟，觀音在那裡
Do you know last…
你知道上次…
you have one Mother Mercy you have given me –
你給我一個觀音像 –
Kuan Yin, same thing, Kuan Yin.
觀音，一樣的，觀音
And She’s the same thing called as Mother of Mercy –
她也被稱為慈悲之母——
and the second one was given by Gregoire recently,
第二個是最近由格雷給的
and you see what’s happening in China.
你可以看到中國發生的事情
So the effects of these
所以這些存在於不同國家、
Deities which existed in different countries at different times
不同時期的神祇的影響
are felt only in Kali Yuga in the best way.
只有在"爭鬥時代"才最能感受到
Now you may say that,
現在你可能會說
“Why should Mother come last to Greece?”
“為什麼母親要最後才來到希臘？”
Because now Athena is in the Sahastrara,
因為現在雅典娜女神在頂輪
so you have to go not in the Nabhi.
所以你不必去臍輪
So I had to bring Sahastrara here, isn’t it?
所以我必須把頂輪帶來這裡，不是嗎？
Sahastrara is the last chakra one has to achieve,
頂輪 是最後一個需要成就的輪穴
so I thought that let Greeks
所以我想讓希臘人
grow up to the Sahastrara point.
成長到頂輪的層次
So we have to establish Sahastrara in Greece
所以我們必須在希臘建立頂輪
and thus it’s a very powerful work we have to do in Greece
所以在希臘 我們必須做這一項非常強大的工作
because actually, at the time
因為實際上，在那個時候
when Athena came here,
當雅典娜女神來到這裡
it was not Sahastrara, it was Nabhi,
那不是頂輪，而是臍輪
because She was actually on the Himalayas, came from Himalayas.
因為她實際上是在喜馬拉雅山，來自喜馬拉雅山
So now to bring Himalaya here,
所以現在要把喜馬拉雅山帶到這裡
or to bring that purity in Greece, is a tremendous task
將那種純淨帶來希臘 那是一項艱辛的任務
and we have very few sahaja yogis.
這裡的霎薩哈嘉瑜伽士非常少
But you see the reaction of the gentleman who came?
你看到那位先生的反應嗎？
And we have formidable job because of these Orthodox…
因為這些迂腐正統的關係，我們的工作非常艱鉅…
most unorthodox,
最不正統
they have no orthodoxy about anything.
他們對任何事情都沒有正統觀念
So we have a problem, big problem,
所以有一個問題，嚴重的問題
how we’ll establish here.
就是我們將如何在這裡建立
The Devaloka was formed here
天界是在這裡形成的
and devas were here; they ruled here, no doubt;
天神在此；毫無疑問，他們統治著這裡；
but in the human awareness they're brought down to the human level.
但在人類意識中，他們被降低到了人類層面
Like Zeus was Parashurama, Parashurama –
像宙斯是帕拉修拉瑪，帕拉修拉瑪 –
the one who was an Incarnation to announce the advent of Shri Rama,
祂的轉世是為了宣告羅摩的降臨
and He came before Shri Ram, died also very much before Shri Ram;
祂在羅摩之前出現，也在羅摩來之前去世；
but they painted Zeus as a man who was a womaniser.
但人們把宙斯描繪成一個好色的男人
So all Gods were brought to the level of human beings,
所有的神祇都被帶到了人類的水平
bestowed with all the weaknesses, you see,
給予了所有人性的弱點
actually decorated with all the weaknesses.
實際上用所有人性的弱點來裝飾這些神祇
And that is responsible for the downfall
這是導致衰敗的原因
because this part of the country
因為這個地區
is on the pattern of Devaloka,
是依照天界的模式
reflection of that, but this Devaloka is now,
反射出來的，但這個天界現在
we see it has become just the opposite
我們看到已經變成了完全相反的樣子
because Deities have been brought down to such a low level,
因為神祇被降到如此低的水平
to such degrading things.
如此的貶低
Even in the mythology also, in India
即使在印度的神話中
talks about Them like this. Not to such an extent;
也這樣談論他們。沒那麼嚴重；
like Zeus, they don’t talk but about Indra they talk.
他們不談論宙斯，但談論因陀羅
And like Indra’s description comes like this:
對因陀羅的描述是這樣的：
that the king Hiranyakashipu’s wife was living…
那位希蘭雅卡希普國王的妻子住在……
his wife… Hiranyakashipu’s wife was a saintly lady
他的妻子……希拉尼亞卡希普的妻子是一位聖潔的女士
and Hiranyakashipu was ruling in the area of
而希拉尼亞卡希普的統治區域
you can say Kandahar and Afghanistan and all these places,
你可以說是坎大哈和阿富汗這些地方
and from here Indra went down
因陀羅是在這裡降生
and took away the wife.
將妻子帶走
I mean They incarnated, the Gods incarnated here,
我的意思是，神祇在這裡轉世
and Indra went down,
因陀羅降生
He took away the wife of Hiranyakashipu with Him, to save Her,
他帶走了希蘭雅卡希普的妻子，為了拯救她
and He went down and stayed in an ashram in Maharashtra
他來到並停留在馬哈拉施特拉邦的一個修道院中
where there’s a river flowing with My name – Nira.
在那有一條流淌著我名字的河流旁 - 尼拉
So now the… see how the combinations are,
現在看看這些組合是怎樣的
the Shandilya Muni who was the guru of My family –
沙丹利亞聖人是我家族的導師 -
that’s why My gotra is Shandilya –
這就是為什麼我家族的階級是沙丹利亞 –
it was in his ashram He stayed.
沙丹利亞住在他的靜修院裡
So the Muni Shandilya told
所以沙丹利亞聖人說道
that, “See, this lady is a very pure lady,
那麼，“你看，這位女士是一位非常純潔的女士
don’t disturb her, and out of her will come a very great saint
不要打擾她，從她身上將會出現一位非常偉大的聖人
who will, by his own devotion,
他將憑藉自己的虔誠
make the Incarnation of Narasimha –
使那羅西瑪的化身 –
this is the god Vishnu which comes as the half-cat –
這是神祇毗濕奴以半貓的形象出現 –
and He will kill this asura.
他將殺死這個阿修羅惡魔
Now, part of the Egypt was also ruled by this Hiranyakashipu,
埃及的一部分也由這位希蘭卡希普統治
part of the Egypt – see how significant everything is.
埃及的一部分——看看一切是多麼有意義
So this Narasimha came
所以這位那羅西瑪降臨了
when…  you know about Prahlada’s story, alright, so this
當，你知道普拉哈拉達的故事吧，所以這
little boy played there around and he made some
小男孩在那裡玩耍，他做了一些
things and there’s a temple very near – you have seen Narasimha’s temple
事情，附近有一座廟宇——你見過那羅西瑪的廟宇
and that you have seen the statue made out of sand?
你有看到那座用沙子做的雕像嗎？
That was made by Prahlad,
那是普拉拉德作的
and he came into the dreams of someone and said that,
他進了某人的夢中並說
“In your temple you please put the statue I have made”,
“在你的寺廟裡請放置我所製作的雕像”
and they went around the Nira river and found it and put it there.
他們繞過尼拉河，找到了雕像並把它放在那裡
So see the relationship, how it is.
所以看看這種關係，是怎樣
Now this Hiranyakashipu was killed by Narasimha.
現在這個希蘭卡希普是被那羅西瑪殺死的
Narasimha, as you know, is the Incarnation of Shri Vishnu,
那羅西瑪，正如你所知，是神祇毗濕奴的化身
because he had, this Hiranyakashipu had, a blessing of Brahmadeva
因為希蘭卡希普得到了布拉馬德瓦的祝福
that not any animal can kill him,
所以沒有任何動物可以殺死他
not any human being can kill him,
也沒有任何人類可以殺死他
not on the land or in the sky,
也不會在陸地上或天空中
and not with any weapon –
不能用任何武器 –
all so many blessings he had taken!
希蘭卡希普所獲得的祝福真是太多了！
He had closed all the lines, you see,
你看，他已經關閉了所有可能的線
so that nobody should kill him,
所以沒有任何人能殺死他
but actually he did not know there are ways and matters.
但實際上他不知道還有其他辦法
So Shri Vishnu took the form of Narasimha,
所以神祇毗濕奴已那羅西瑪的形式降生
is that He became the simha,
他變成獅子
means the ‘lion’, and the lower portion of a man.
意思是“獅子”，以及人類的下半身
And it so happened that Hiranyakashipu asked Prahlada,
而且剛好 希拉尼亞卡希普問了普拉哈達
“Where is your God?” He said, “He’s everywhere.”
“你的神在哪裡？”他說：“祂無處不在。”
So he said, “Alright, is He in this pillar?”
所以他說：“好吧，祂在這根柱子裡嗎？”
He said, “Yes, He’s in this pillar also.”
他說：“是的，祂也在這根柱子裡。”
So he hit the pillar – see, the pillar
所以他把柱子撞倒——看，那根柱子
must have been the same style as you make, Greek style,
一定是和你們做的風格一樣，希臘風格
pillar of stone,
石柱
so he knew that in the pillar how can anybody be, it’s a stone –
所以他知道在柱子裡面，怎麼會有人呢，這是一塊石頭 –
he hit it and the pillar broke, out of which came out Narasimha
他打壞它，柱子破了，從裡面出現了那羅西瑪
with long hands and claws,
有著長長的手和爪子
and He took that Hiranyakashipu
他把希拉尼亞卡希普抱起來
and put him on His lap, because neither on the sky nor on the ground
把他放在自己的膝蓋上，因為既不在天空也不在地面上
and with His claws, because they were not weapons,
然後用他的爪子，因為它們不是武器
He opened his stomach and killed him.
打開了希拉尼亞卡希普的肚子，殺了他
So, because he was also ruling in Egypt,
所以，因為他也在埃及統治
the people of Egypt made their…
埃及人民做了他們的…
they were Assyrians – Assyrians are asuras,
他們是亞述人 – 亞述人是阿修羅
they were the ones who were asuras,
他們就曾是那些阿修羅惡魔
that’s why they were called Assyrians –
這就是為什麼他們被稱為亞述人 –
so they made the statue of their god Sphinx
所以當他們製作他們的神斯芬克斯的雕像
the other way round than Narasimha.
與那羅西馬恰好相反
So the upper part of the Sphinx is that of man,
所以斯芬克斯的上半部分是人的形象
and the lower part of that statue is that of lion.
而那座雕像的下半部分是獅子的形象
This is very ancient story I’m telling.
我現在說的是一個非常古老的故事
So how the Greeks went to India long time back,
所以希臘人如何在很久以前前往印度
because all these devas were Greeks –
因為所有這些天神都是希臘人 –
and these devas were, like Indra,
這些天神就像因陀羅一樣
what He did, and Varuna and all these things.
祂所做的，以及神祇瓦魯納
But I think there… because
但我想那裡…因為
the whole idea got perverted, whole thing,
整個想法變得扭曲，整件事
they could not see the proper image of their...
他們無法看到神祇正確的形象...
of their...faces in their meditation
在他們的冥想中...神祇的面孔
because they perverted them
因為它們被扭曲了
so they could not see, and they saw perverted faces.
以至於他們無法看見，他們看到的是扭曲的形象
They saw them nude and that kind of thing,
他們看到裸體之類
which was all their own imagination
這完全是他們自己的想像力
working, because they were indulging into all kinds of immoral things
因為他們沉迷於各種不道德的事情
so they made it absolutely, what you call a ...
所以他們把它做得絕對，所謂...
very immoral type of relationships and things among them.
在他們之間存有非常不道德的關係類型
So that was their own ideas and they put it.
所以那是他們自己的想法，把它付諸實行
But also, as a result of that, they could never see
同時，因為這個原因，他們永遠無法看的清楚
the body or the faces of these devatas properly.
這些神祇的身體或面孔
So they made them more like…
所以他們把神祇弄得…
I mean quite ugly-looking faces they made.
我的意思是他們做的相當醜陋的面孔
Like I have some Poseidon they have made here
就像我在這裡看到一些陶瓷物
which they gave it to My husband also – it’s not at all
他們也給我丈夫——完全不像
like Varuna, I can tell you.
神祇瓦魯納，我可以告訴你
So… and absolutely nude, you know; it’s so embarrassing.
完全的裸體，你知道；真是太尷尬了
They gave it to My husband and he didn’t know where to look,
他們給了我丈夫，他都不知道該看哪裡
and I just started laughing because he’s a very shy man, My husband.
我開始笑，因為他是一個非常害羞的男人，我的丈夫
And he had to put it in his office, you see,
然後他必須放在他的辦公室
hidden somewhere and it looks very funny.
藏在某個地方，看起來非常有趣
And he was saying, “Why not we use a kind of a...
他還說：“為什麼我們不用...
covering with some silver?” I said, “It’s an antique
“用一些銀器來覆蓋？”我說，“這是一件古董。”
they have reproduced; you can’t do it to an antique.”
“他們已經複製了；你不能這樣對待一件古董。”
He said, “Alright; where should I put it?”
他說，‘好吧；那我應該把它放哪裡？’”
I said, “Put it in some corridor there.”
我說：“把它放在那個走廊。”
So with such expense they gave it
所以他們花了這麼多錢買了它
but My husband was quite upset about it, you see,
我丈夫對此卻相當不開心
and every time he sees this gentleman he says,
每次他看到這個陶瓷像，他都會說
“You know, this gentleman is no good.”
“你知道，這個陶瓷像真不好。”
Alright. So then, this part of the history is there.
好的。所以，這段歷史就在這裡
On that history stands the modern Greek.
現代希臘的歷史基礎
So, if you see from Socrates to Christ,
所以，從蘇格拉底到基督
people had evolved we think,
我們認為人們已經進化了
but they also crucified Christ,
但他們也釘死了基督
so what was their evolution?
所以人類的演化是什麼？
Though, if you see what Christ preached and what…
不過，如果你看看基督所宣講的和…
I’m sorry, what Christ preached and Socrates preached,
我很抱歉，基督所宣講的和蘇格拉底所宣講的
there is much difference
之間有很大的差異
because Socrates talked in parables, not openly,
因為耶穌是用比喻來講話，而不是公開地講
while Socrates talked in a very open way,
而蘇格拉底以非常開放的方式談話
in an open discussion, in open understanding.
開放的討論，開放的理解
That shows only that the people could understand what He was saying.
這顯示出當時人們能夠理解他所說的話
But still He was also killed;
但他仍然被殺了；
Socrates also was given poison and He was also killed.
蘇格拉底也被給予了毒藥，他也被殺了
So that shows that, at that time also, the people in charge,
這顯示出，在那個時候，掌政的人
or at the helm of affairs, didn’t know what was reality.
或者說在政務管理者中，並不知道什麼是真實(實相)
So now, from Christ to Socrates and from Socrates to Me,
所以，從基督到蘇格拉底，然後從蘇格拉底到我
we can say this way that we are talking about it,
我們可以這樣說，我們正在談論
though Socrates came in the year – how much B.C. He was?
蘇格拉底是在哪一年來的？公元前多少年？
Yogi: About 500 years before Christ
瑜伽士：大約在基督之前 500 年
500 before Christ;
公元前 500 年；
so might be that Christ must have felt that Socrates,
所以基督可能感受到蘇格拉底
He talked so openly, so nicely to people
蘇格拉底對人們如此坦率，如此友好地交談
as because He was Primordial Master.
因為他是太初導師
He realised it, so He talked in parables.
基督意識到了這一點，所以他用寓言式來講話
He thought that, “No use talking straight like Socrates”
他認為，“像蘇格拉底那樣直言無隱是沒有用的”
because… you see they are very straightforward people;
因為……你看，他們是非常直率的人；
the Primordial Masters have to be very, very…
太初導師必須非常非常…
they are by nature extremely straightforward.
他們本質上是極其直接的
Even today’s… those who were real gurus,
即使今天…那些真正的導師
they would not accept any person,
他們不接受任何人
they would throw away, they would beat people.
他們會把人扔掉，他們會打人
Even musicians in India, those who are great masters,
即使是印度的音樂家，那些偉大的老師
they would beat their disciples if they played something wrong;
如果他們的弟子做錯了什麼，他們會打罵他們；
like very harsh people.
非常嚴厲的人
So it was alright for Socrates also to tell things very
所以蘇格拉底所說的
plain and simple and all that, but still He was killed.
都是非常簡單明瞭，但他仍然被殺了
And then Christ, who was 500 years later came.
然後基督在五百年後來了
See, He saw the point
他看到了重點
that no use talking – because He came at Agya –
沒有用談論 - 因為他來到額輪 -
talking in that way.
以那種方式談話
If you tell somebody, “Don’t do like this”,
如果你告訴某人，“不要這樣做”
even reason it out like Socrates did,
甚至像蘇格拉底那樣講道理
He is the master of logic, you can call Him;
他是邏輯的大師，你可以這麼稱呼他；
the whole logic system comes from Him,
整個邏輯系統都源自於他
He’s a master of logic.
他是邏輯的大師
But despite that, it did not appeal to the logic of the people who were at the helm of affairs.
儘管如此，這邏輯並未吸引那些政務管理者
So they have no logic in their heads, you see, they are just rationalist.
所以他們腦中沒有邏輯，你看，他們只是理性主義者
Rationality is blindness but there’s no logic.
理性主義是盲目，沒有邏輯
So because there is no logic they killed Him.
因為沒有邏輯，他們殺了蘇格拉底
And Christ understood that there is no logic
基督明白人們沒有邏輯
with these people so better talk to them in parables.
所已與這些人交談時，最好用寓言來表達
So He talked to them in parables,
所以他用寓言與他們交談
but still they killed Him.
但他們仍然殺了他
[ Helm! ] The authorities, they couldn’t bear, they thought
[ 海爾姆！ ] 當局無法忍受，他們認為
He’s becoming very powerful, or whatever it was. The Jews themselves
祂變得非常強大。猶太人自己
were very funny, and they did it.
也非常怪異，然後他們做的
So in Sahaja Yoga, what I decided that at least
所以在霎哈嘉瑜伽，我決定至少
I should give Realisation to people first,
我應該先帶給人們自覺
and then I can talk to them whatever I like.
然後我才可以隨心所欲地與他們交談
Now, I’m talking to you everything
像現在，我在和你談論一切
and you are understanding it because you are Realised souls,
你能理解是因為你是已覺醒的靈
but I cannot talk this to an ordinary person.
我無法對普通人談論這些
So we have two types of people: one who are Sahaja Yogis,
所以有兩種類型的人：一種是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and one who are not.
和那些不是瑜珈士
Of course there are some Sahaja Yogis who are not very worthy of this,
當然，也有些霎哈嘉瑜伽士並不很好
I agree, and they may just go back or something,
我同意，他們可能沒法待住
but you can become worthy of understanding all this knowledge
但你也可以變得有價值 得以理解所有這些知識的人
because your Kundalini can make you so capable
因為你的昆達里尼可以讓你如此有能力
and your Sahastrara so good that you can absorb what I’m saying,
你的頂輪如此優秀，你可以吸收我所說的
and can logically see what I’m saying is true,
你可以從邏輯上看出我所說的是真實的
and you can also verify it, whether it is true or not.
你也可以驗證它的真假
So this stage of yours, I think, is the highest stage of awareness
所以我認為，你們的這個階段是意識的最高階段
where collectively you are understanding Me.
你們可以共同地理解我
The situation is not so bad as that was
即使在基督時代
even at the time of Christ.
情況也沒有那麼糟
Before that, at Socrates’ time, I think,
在那之前，在蘇格拉底的時代，我認為
He was the only wise man going around.
他是周遭唯一的智者
There was nobody else, seems to Me, had any wisdom.
在我看來，沒有其他人有任何智慧
Even His disciples, you see, like Plato –
甚至他的門徒，像柏拉圖 –
he went off his head, then Aristotle went off his head.
他失去了理智，然後亞里士多德也失去了理智
Both of them, really,
其實他們兩個
tried to have their own arbitrary additions
嘗試用他們自己的任意添加
which were all absolutely.
到這些絕對的
But He talked absolutely…
蘇格拉底有談到絕對……
Socrates talked absolutely about gods and everything,
蘇格拉底毫無保留地談論神和一切事物
and talked so openly.
非常坦率
Then, in the same way, we can say,
同樣的方式，我們可以說
the Primordial Master state is that
太初導師的狀態
we have Mohammad Sahib. He was also killed;
穆罕默德。他也被殺了；
He was also killed because He told the truth.
他被殺是因為他說了真話
Then came Nanaka;
然後那納克來了；
He was not killed but nobody bothered about Him,
他沒有被殺，但沒有人聽他的
and the people who really follow Him are just
而那些追隨他的人也走上
in the opposite direction.
相反的方向
Supposing He was saying, “Come this way”;
假設他說：“往這邊來”；
so they are going in that way.
他們就朝另個方向走
You find even same thing with Christ;
你會發現相同的事情也發生在基督上；
if Christ said, “Come this way” the Christians are going that way.
如果基督說：“往這邊來”，基督徒就會往那邊去
Every religion is just the same.
每個宗教都是一樣的
Same with Krishna’s Gita.
克里希納的《梵歌書》也是
Those who preach Gita are just…
傳講《梵歌書》的那些人只是…
if Krishna is standing here and saying,
如果克里希納站在這裡說
“Come this way” Gita is saying, they are preaching Gita
“這邊走”梵歌書說，他們在宣講梵歌書
going down, taking people down.
下降，帶著人們往下滑
So it is common with all religions
這在所有宗教都是普遍的
that they have always used the name of prophets
他們一直使用先知
and of all the Incarnations just to make money
以及所有的降世神祇的名字 都只是為了賺錢
and to take everybody to hell; straightforward march to hell you see.
並將每個人帶到地獄；這是一條直通地獄的路
So, now those who are alert about it,
現在那些對此保持警覺的人
and those who have seen that this is all nonsense are in Sahaja Yoga
以及那些看到這一切都是胡說八道的人都在霎哈嘉瑜伽中
and sahaja yogis can’t do that
霎哈嘉瑜珈士無法這麼做
because they have come quite a long way now on this side,
因為他們現在在這一邊已經走了相當長的路
so they are going to pull out many others to that side
所以他們將會把許多人帶出來
instead of going themselves down.
而不是自己下去
So this is the situation today, and that’s why I say Greece
這就是今天的情況，這就是我為什麼說希臘
is a very wonderful area where we can work it out.
是一個非常美好的地方，我們可以在這裡解決問題
If Athena could be awakened here,
如果雅典娜女神能在這裡被喚醒
this place could be of very great help to us.
這個地方對我們來說會非常有幫助
Now there are very balanced Greek people,
現在有非常平衡的希臘人
they have great sense of art because of Right-side Swadhishthana;
他們因為右脈的腹輪而擁有很好的藝術感；
also they have lots of qualities of
他們還有很多的特質
understanding the worthlessness of
理解
too much indulgences and all that. It is so.
過度的放縱和所有這些是沒有價值的。就是如此
But the immorality grew,
但不道德的行為開始增長
now, because they started copying Westerners;
因為他們開始模仿西方人；
otherwise the women here were very moral women.
否則這裡的女性都是非常有道德的女性
This is only in these twenty years this change has come.
這二十年來發生的變化
Before that the women were very moral,
在此之前，女性非常有道德
very good women lived here,
這裡生活著非常善良的女性
and some of them are now in India as I told you, they came with Alexander,
正如我告訴你的，他們現在有些人在印度，他們是跟隨亞歷山大而來的
and they were very good husbands and wives and very good families.
他們是非常好的丈夫和妻子，並且有著非常好的家庭
This is only – I don’t know why – about twenty years
這只是——我不知道為什麼——大約二十年
or twenty-five years at the most, you can say,
或者最多二十五年
the Kali Yuga is showing its effects here also,
"爭鬥時代"在這裡也顯示出它的影響力
but it’s a very solid country and still they respect,
但這是一個非常穩固的國家，他們仍然尊重
respect a woman who has character; respect her.
尊重一位有品格的女性；尊重她
They may use a woman who has no character
他們可能會利用一位沒有品格的女性
but they respect the woman who has character
但他們尊重有品格的女性
and also respect the mother.
也尊重母親
So there are lots of qualities in this country
所以這個國家有很多特質
which are still existing,
仍然存在
in some places lingering, and some places effective.
在某些地方持續存在，在某些地方非常有效
So the job of Sahaja Yogis is to, somehow or other,
所以霎哈嘉瑜伽士的工作是，無論如何
evoke that integrating force in them of the Athena,
喚起他們內心的整合力量，像雅典娜女神一樣
and I’m sure you can purify this country.
我相信你可以淨化這個國家
May God bless you!
願上帝保佑你！
Alexander was two hundred before Christ…
亞歷山大在基督之前兩百年…
a hundred, two hundred before Christ.
一百，兩百年前
He was very much respected in India, always,
他在印度非常受人尊敬，總是如此
Alexander was very much respected in India,
亞歷山大在印度非常受人尊敬
and because he went away
而且因為他離開了
and he didn’t take away anything from India.
他並沒有從印度帶走任何東西
Like any other invaders who came, who just looted us, he did not.
像其他來的侵略者一樣，他只是掠奪我們，亞歷山大並沒有這樣做
I think he got quite detached
我認為 來到印度之後
after coming to India. Anybody who has
他變得相當超然。相對其他來入侵印度的人
come to invade India, and has really gained something
亞歷山大真的從
out of the spirituality of India, was Alexander;
印度的靈性中有收獲；
otherwise the English lived for three hundred in India,
否則英國人在印度生活了三百年
three hundred years.
三百年
Nothing went into their heads, nothing.
什麼都進不了他們的腦袋，什麼都沒有
Three hundred years! Can you believe it?
三百年！你能相信嗎？
They used to laugh at everything, they used to make fun of everything,
他們嘲笑一切，對一切都取笑
nothing went into their heads.
什麼都進不了他們的腦袋
But so many Greeks stayed on because they liked India very much,
但是有很多希臘人因為非常喜歡印度而留下來
so they stayed back, they wouldn’t come back.
所以他們留下來，不再回去
So many are there even now living in the forests.
現在仍然有很多人住在森林裡
So, this is something, is the sensitivity, the awareness,
所以，這是一種敏感性，意識
which has grown through times in the Greek people.
這在希臘人民中隨著時間的推移而增長
You can see in the character of Alexander, how he was.
你可以在亞歷山大的性格中看到，他是怎樣的
There’s a poet in India called Chandav Rai,
在印度有位詩人叫做昌達夫·賴
who was at the time of Alexander.
他生活在亞歷山大的時代
Alexander brought him here, honoured him, kept him here,
亞歷山大把他帶到這裡，尊敬他，讓他留在這裡
he was here, and he wrote poems about Alexander,
他曾在這裡，並且寫了關於亞歷山大的詩
about his greatness and things, praised him so well.
讚美他的偉大，讚揚他如此之好
I mean I can’t think of English people carrying any Indian as a poet
我的意思是，我無法想像英國人會把任何印度人視為詩人
to England;
帶到英國；
there’s no question. I mean, they didn’t…
毫無疑問。我是說，他們沒有…
and the sign of awareness is this, that
而意識的指標就是這個，這樣
you don’t respect anybody else, you say, “Oh, I am the greatest”.
當你不尊重其他人，說：“哦，我是最偉大的”
Then you cannot see the goodness of other people.
那麼你就看不到其他人的善良
Same with Portuguese. Of course, Vasco de Gama was a simple man
葡萄牙人也是如此。當然，瓦斯科·達·伽馬是一個簡單的人
and when he came first to India, he saw Indians
當他第一次來到印度時，他看到了印度人
and he went to Goa and he saw the temple of the Goddess
然後他去了果阿，看到女神的廟宇
there, is the Shanta Durga’s,
那裡是和平女神的廟宇
so he went back and told his king that,
他回去告訴他的國王
“They are all Christians because they follow the Mother.
“他們都是基督徒，因為他們跟隨母親
They are not Muslims”.
他們不是穆斯林”
So simple he was.
他是如此簡單
“There’s no need to make them Christians.
“沒有必要讓他們成為基督徒
They are already Christians because they follow Mother”.
他們已經是基督徒，因為他們跟隨母親。”
He was a nice man.
他是一個好人
But Portuguese also never learned anything much,
但葡萄牙人也從來沒有學到太多的東西
but still certain respect they showed, like
他們曾表現出某種尊重，比如說
the name of Bombay is Mumbai.
孟買的名字是孟買
They still call it Mumbai.
他們仍然稱它為孟買
many words Mumbai
許多與孟買有關的詞
is the Mumba. Mumba-ayi, Mumbai  is the name.
是孟巴。孟巴阿依，孟買就是這個名字
Means she is the Mother of Mumba.
意思是她是女神是母親
Like ‘ayi’ is the Mother,
像「ayi」就是母親
so they call it Mumbai –
所以他們稱之為孟買 –
is the name of the Goddess.
是女神的名字
So they didn’t want to change it.
他們不想改名
And in Portugal, when I went, they were saying “Mumbai”.
在葡萄牙，我去的時候，他們在說「孟買」
is the Mumba. Mumba-ayi is the name.
是孟巴。孟巴-阿依是這個名字
“After all, it’s the name of the Goddess; isn’t it?”
「畢竟，這是女神的名字；不是嗎？」
I said, “It is.”
我說：“就是這樣。”
But the English came, called it “Bombay”- finished.
但英國人來了之後，改稱為“棒買”——結束了
So you see the… see the awareness,
所以你看……看這意識
you can see the awareness of people
你可以看到人們的意識
because they were so aware about the serenity,
因為他們對寧靜非常有覺察
about the holiness, about the auspiciousness and all that,
對神聖、對吉祥以及所有這些事物的覺察
so they said, “How can we call it Bombay
他們說：“我們怎麼能叫它棒買呢？”
because it is the name of the Goddess?”
因為這是女神的名字？”
Just think- the depth, no? “We cannot call.”
想想看——深度，不是嗎？“我們不能這樣叫。”
But the English could have gone and found out
但英國人本可以去了解一下
what is this place called, why is it called Mumbai.
這個地方叫什麼，為什麼叫孟買
But they did not.
但他們沒有
But even if they had found, I don’t think they would have
但即使他們找到了，我也不認為他們會
kept it as Mumbai. They would not have
保持這個名字為孟買。他們不會
because, you see, that respect
因為，你看，那種尊重
for serenity and all these things,
為了平靜和所有這些事情
somehow or other, in these people who ruled us, it was not there.
不知怎的，在這些統治我們的英國人身上，這並不存在
Now the children of Britain
現在英國的孩子們
are better, are very different, very different.
好些了，完全不同，非常不同
But those who ruled us had no respect at all.
但那些統治我們的人根本沒有尊重
They would only go to church, and nothing, no respect.
他們只會去教堂，什麼都不做，沒有尊重
While the Greeks had always respect for Indians,
像希臘人一直對印度人抱有尊重
they came with respect.
他們帶著尊重而來
Now, the respect, also, is a kind of an awareness within us.
現在，尊重也是我們內心的一種覺知
And now, as the time has passed,
而現在，隨著時間的推移
I find Britishers have respect for others,
我發現英國人開始對他人有尊重
they’re respecting, many.
他們尊重很多人
I mean, I would not say all, but quite a lot, isn’t it.
我的意思是，我不會說全部，但相當多，不是嗎？
Well, what do you say? He has not met any.
那麼，你怎麼說？他沒有遇到任何人
Yes, that’s the part lacking- respect.
是的，缺少的部分就是尊重
That is the part lacking in England.
這是英國所缺乏的部分
And imagine in the heart, if there is no respect,
想像一下，如果心輪沒有尊重
then what sort of a heart it must be?
那麼這是什麼樣的心輪呢？
The whole world can get ruined by that heart.
整個世界都可能因為那個心輪而毀滅
So that’s the thing – one has to create respect:
所以這就是重點——人必須創造尊重：
respecting others, respecting their culture,
尊重他人，尊重他們的文化
respecting their lifestyle.
尊重他們的生活方式
But, I mean whatever you may say, but theoretically it is there;
但是，我的意思是無論你怎麼說，理論上它是存在的；
may not be in practice. Theoretically it is working,
實際中可能不會。理論上它是有效的
because you’re not supposed to insult anybody
因為你不應該侮辱任何人
who is from the ethnic group and all that is there legally,
誰來自那個族群，所有的事情都是合法的
theoretically; but in practice it is not,
理論上是這樣；但在實踐中並非如此
I agree; but theoretically it is working.
我同意；但理論上它是有效的
You can’t insult somebody because he’s a black man or he’s
你不能因為他是黑人或他是某個民族群體而侮辱某人，根據法律，你不能這樣做
an ethnic group, you cannot, under law, you cannot do it.
你不能，根據法律，你不能這樣做
So that is there but just theory.
所以這是存在的，但只是理論
But still, awareness-wise also, people are aware.
但仍然，在意識上，人們也是有意識的
I know of so many of them who were sitting in the sun
我知道有很多人曾經坐在太陽下
and fasting for South Africa.
為南非禁食
So between the South African awareness
所以在南非的意識和
and British awareness, we must say, we should be proud
英國的意識之間，我們應該感到自豪
that in British awareness there is lot of sense,
在英國的認知中，有很多意義
and that sense, once it comes to the point of respecting others,
一旦涉及到尊重他人
I think it can transform the whole world.
我認為這可以改變整個世界
But I don’t know how I have to do it, I’ve tried.
我不知道我該怎麼做，我已經嘗試了
It has to be respect.
必須要有尊重
It is not insulting now,
不是侮辱
but it is not positive respect.
但也不是積極的尊重
So one has to learn how to positively respect;
所以人們必須學會如何積極地尊重；
at least Sahaja Yogis must be positively respected.
至少霎哈嘉瑜伽士必須受到積極的尊重
This is what I have been talking about,
這就是我一直在談論的
about Buddha, about truth, about respect.
關於佛陀，關於真理，關於尊重
But once you know that they are Sahaja Yogis, one has to respect.
一旦你知道他們是霎哈嘉瑜伽士，就必須尊重
And this one has to learn from the Greeks
必須向希臘人學習這一點
because still they have a sense of respect.
因為他們仍然有一種尊重感
They know how to respect, isn’t it?
他們知道如何尊重，不是嗎？
That part is there, that one has to learn.
那一部分是存在的，我們需要學習的
Even the Egyptians are, and also the Chinese,
甚至埃及人和中國人也是如此
because out of all these years of traditional growth,
因為在這些年來的傳統增長中
they have realised one thing: that if you have to really
他們意識到一件事：如果你真的想要
exist in this world you have to learn how to respect others.
在這個世界上生存，你必須學會如何尊重他人
And respect is something from your heart.
尊重是來自你的內心
Like the Japanese have no respect for anyone
不是像日本人那樣 對任何人都沒有尊重
but they’ll go and bow ten times,
但他們會鞠躬十次
don’t know when to stop if they bow, and if you bow they’ll go on,
不知道何時該停止，如果你鞠躬他們會繼續
permanently, so it’s best if you stop.
永遠地，所以最好是你先停
But it’s artificial; it’s not real.
那是人造的；不是真實的
So it should come from your innate being to respect others,
這應該來自你內在的本性去尊重他人
and when that works out then
當這樣運作時，然後
your awareness has definitely reached a very high state,
你的意識確實達到了非常高的狀態
high state of understanding of Divinity.
對神性的高理解狀態
So then you come to a point of respecting the Adi Shakti
所以你來到了一個尊重太初之母的時刻
and then, when you have respect, it’s not artificial respect,
然後，當你有尊重時，不是虛假的尊重
it’s not artificial, it should be from your heart.
不是虛假的，是發自內心的
And once you start doing that your awareness will improve.
一旦你開始這樣做，你的覺察力就會提高
And that it’s not what you get,
不是你拿到
it’s not what you have,
不是你有的
but what you give to yourself by respecting.
而是通過尊重自己
And this respect in which transform you completely, I can tell you,
而這種尊重會徹底改變你，我可以告訴你
because there’s a big understanding
因為現在你和神聖之間有了很大的理解
and I’m sure everything will work out very well.
我相信一切會非常順利地發展
The way the Deities respect the Adi Shakti, if you also
如果你也學會了神明對太初之母的尊重
learn that respect, then things will work out.
那麼事情就會順利進行
And I think Greeks will lead us very well,
我認為希臘人會很好地引領我們
the whole of Europe, in this respect; I’m sure about it.
在這方面整個歐洲；我對此深信不疑
May God bless you!
願主保佑你